Ann Messenger fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Teaching materials, 1960 - 1981; F-176-4; 12 cm of textual records
  - Freshman English: lesson plans, Bucknell 1960-1961, and speech 1-A University of California 1962, vol. 1, 1960 - 1962; F-176-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 176-11)
  - Freshman English: lesson plans, Bucknell 1960-1961, and speech 1-A University of California 1962, vol. 2, 1960 - 1962; F-176-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 176-11)
  - San Francisco State 1964: Humanities, vol. 1, 1963 - 1964; F-176-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 176-11)
  - San Francisco State 1964: Humanities, vol. 2, 1963 - 1964; F-176-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 176-11)
  - Poems for English 6.02, San Francisco State, spring 1965, F-176-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 176-11)
  - English 305, Drama (for engineers), UBC, 1967-1968, and SFU #103 (Mod. Drama): lectures and tutorials, Fall 1968, F-176-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - 18th Century graduate seminar (Drama), 1969 - 1970; F-176-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - English 103, SFU, Fall 1970/Spring 1971: modern drama, lectures and tutorial notes, and lectures on short stories (101), and poems (102), vol. 1, 1970 - 1971; F-176-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - English 103, SFU, Fall 1970/Spring 1971: modern drama, lectures and tutorial notes, and lectures on short stories (101), and poems (102), vol. 2, 1970 - 1971; F-176-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - English 203: Poetry Survey Lectures, Fall 1974 and Spring 1972, SFU, 1972 - 1974; F-176-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - English 205, 1979; F-176-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
  - SFU: 312 EV Shakespeare, 80-1, 312 Shakespeare, 81-3, 1980 - 1981; F-176-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
- Published works, 1972 - 1990; F-176-5; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of publications and excerpts of publications containing academic articles and papers by Messenger, and a copy of a bibliographical entry for "Gender at Work."
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist. Items are arranged chronologically acording to date of publication.
  The files are open with no restrictions.
  An item list is available.
  - Article: Damnation at Christmas: John Herbert's "Fortune and Men's Eyes", 1972; F-176-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    John Herbert; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item2.
  - Article: Adam Pos'd, 1974; F-176-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item3.
  - Article: Selected Nightingales and an "Augustan" Sensibility, 1980; F-176-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item4.
  - Article: Publishing Without Perishing: Lady Winchilsea's "Miscellany Poems" of 1713, 1981; F-176-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    Finch, Anne Kingsmill; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item5.
  - Paper: Dryden's Ode and Anne Killigrew's Poems: A Problem of Praise", 1982; F-176-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    Killigrew, Anne; John Dryden; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item6.
  - Paper: Rasselas Redux, or, Back to Abyssinia, 1983; F-176-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 176-12)
    Samuel Johnson; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item7.
  - Article: Daughter of Shenstone: Being a Brief Life of Mary Whateley Darwall, 1987; F-176-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
    Mary Whateley Darwall; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item8.
  - Paper: Visible Language: Eighteenth Century Language Theory and Savage Gestures, 1988; F-176-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item9.
  - Article: Re-appraisals: Frances Sherdian and the Canon Then and Now, 1989; F-176-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
    Frances Sheridan; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item10.
  - Bibliographical entry:"Gender at Work: Four Women Writers of the Eighteenth Century", 1990; F-176-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-176-item11.
- Photographs, 1960 - 1974; F-176-6; 18 photographs
  Series consists of photographs of Ann and Bill Messenger and their house in Point Grey, as well as photographs of Ann's parents and their visits to Ann and Bill in Vancouver in the mid-1960s.
  Photographs are arranged chronologically.
  Messenger, William Edmund; Lillian Parshall; Raymond Parshall
  - Photographs, 1960 - 1974; F-176-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 176-16)
- William E. Messenger correspondence, 1949-1956, 1970; F-176-7; 5 cm of textual records 5 photographs; General note: photographs are located in file 2.
  Series consists of Bill Messenger's incoming correspondence, 1946 to 1956, and outgoing correspondence, 1950 to 1954, and 1970. Incoming correspondence includes letters from friends, his aunt, and the University of Washington, which he attended from 1955 to 1956. Series also includes report cards received by Bill while attending Everett Senior High School, between 1946 and 1948. Outgoing correspondence consists mainly of letters and photographs sent to his parents, Edmund and Inge Therese (Tess) Messenger, and to his grandmother and his aunt while he was in the air force, 1951 to 1954. Correspondence pertains to family matters, as well as his air force training and activities.
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist. Files are arranged chronologically.
  Photographs have been left in folders with correspondence, so as not to lose their context.
  For other material relating to Bill Messenger, see the William Messenger fonds at the University of British Columbia Archives.
  - Letters to Bill, 1950s, 1949 - 1956; F-176-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
  - Letters written by Bill, 1950-1954, 1970 [includes photographs], vol. 1, 1951 - 1954; F-176-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
  - Letters written by Bill, 1950-1954, 1970, vol. 2, 1950 - 1970; F-176-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 176-13)
- Edmund E. Messenger correspondence, 1917 - 1969; F-176-8; 28 cm of textual records 13 photographs 7 negatives; Conservation: Some of the photographs from ca. 1917-1919 have faded. General note: photographs are located in files 1, 3, 7, and 9.
  Series consists of correspondence of Ann Messenger's father-in-law, Edmund (Ed) Messenger. Includes correspondence to his family and a journal written during his military service in World War One. Activities, events and topics documented include his military work and Radio Operator training; life on board ship; his travels; his view of war events; his trial and acquittal for disregarding military censorship protocol; celebrations at the end of the war; the burning and sinking of the USS Pennsylvania; as well as his military service after the war and his father's efforts on his behalf to have him discharged after the war. Includes postcards collected during his service, and photographs of Ed, fellow service men, and places that he travelled to during his service. Later correspondence includes a letter to his mother in 1951 concerning his son Bill's activities, correspondence to Bill in the 1950s, and correspondence to Bill and Ann in the 1960s, relating mainly to his activities and those of family friends. Although a few early letters include accounts of his wife Tess and her activities, the majority of this correspondence dates from after her death in January 1964.
  Except for a few photographs already separated from any accompanying correspondence, photographs have been left in folders with correspondence, so as not to lose their context.
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI) [includes photograph], vol. 1, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 176-14)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI), vol. 2, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 176-14)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI) [includes photographs], vol. 3, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 176-14)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI), vol. 4, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 176-14)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI), vol. 5, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 176-15)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI), vol. 6, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 176-15)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger (WWI): postcards and photographs, vol. 7, 1917 - 1919; F-176-8-0-0-7 (Archival box - small 176-16)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger, 1951-1969, vol. 1, 1951, 1961-1965; F-176-8-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 176-15)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger, 1951-1969 [includes photographs], vol. 2, 1964 - 1966; F-176-8-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 176-15)
  - Letters from Ed E. Messenger, 1951-1969, vol. 3, 1956 - 1969; F-176-8-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 176-15)